KELVIN NGURE

Software Engineer

Ngure.kelvin@live.com +254 724634854 Kelvin Ngure | LinkedIn Kelvinfox1 | GitHub

Profile

Dedicated and experienced passionate innovator, programmer, and entrepreneur with over 4 years working as a programmer, CTO, project manager, chief product design, engineering design in technology environments. Adept in making design thinking, human-centred design while providing optimal use of resources. Bringing forth advanced scheduling skills, allowing for the effective management of busy schedules. Committed to helping technology enterprises reach success by providing them with superior administrative and technical services. With specialization in robotics, blockchain technology, website development.

Work History

Software Engineer at Twenifo technologies, Nairobi

May 2022 – Present

- Developing and maintaining all server side network components
- Ensuring optimal performance of the central database and responsiveness to frontend request
- Collaborating with frontend developers on the integration of elements
- Designing customer facing UI and backend service for various business process
- Developed an algorithm to parse resume and use machine learning to review and offer instant feedback based on expert parameters
- Developing high-performance applications by writing testable, reusable, and efficient code.
- Implementing effective security protocols, data protection measures, and storage solutions.
- Running diagnostic tests, repairing defects, and providing technical support.
- Documenting Node.js processes, including database schemas, as well as preparing reports.
- Recommending and implementing improvements to processes and technologies.
- Keeping informed of advancements in the field of Node.js development.

Lead Programmer at MODUGREENS, Nairobi

January 2021 — December 2021

- Responsible for UI /UX designs
- Created the backend API for the client(Angular)
- Built the responsive website using Angular framework
- Designed the circuit for the embedded systems.
- Implemented the circuit for the embedded systems.
- Deployed the applications to play store account.

Lead Programmer and CTO at Circularity Space, Nairobi January 2020 - Present

- Tasked with Software Design and Implementation of user application for reward of points on every disposal redeemable for cash or discount of Product. This helped incentivise people on waste recycling
- Integrated deep learning algorithm for image recognition using Arduino sensors that saw the on boarding of Coca Cola Bottling Company Embakasi as partners in the piloting stage
- Worked on backup and recovery strategies using RMAN
- Through pitch decks, we were able to emerge second runners up at the Hult prize start-up challenge.
- Responsible for UI /UX designs
- Created the backend API for the client(React Native)
- Created and maintain the firebase Firestore
- Deployed the applications to play store account

Lead Programmer at SBO Research Ltd, Nairobi

June 2019 – June 2020

- Designed and developed a new Integrated Operations Platform tool through Agile
 Methodologies, Reactjs, Nodejs and Firebase to efficiently collect, analyse and visualize raw
 data resulting in an increase of company revenue
- Proficiently troubleshot simple to complex technological issues for the assigned projects, achieving over 90% customer satisfaction rate
- Responsible for developing different databases at various stages of implementation of Projects
- Migration of existing SQL user data to No-SQL architecture that saw reduced overhead time on consecutive API calls
- Documented all supported systems and application to effectively train new and existing members

Junior Data Analyst at Transform Research Africa February 2018 – May 2019

- Took part in Data entry, team supervision on a part time basis for the organization, worked on research projects from Diageo plc (Guinness manufacturers), conducted in Ethiopia, Ghana, Nigeria and Kenya.
- Offered Technical support when required and helped in report writing and carrying out instruction from the senior Departments

Projects

Frontend

- https://kelvinfox1.github.io/Aweza/index.html (Tailwind CSS + html + JavaScript)
- https://github.com/Kelvinfox1/SBO-IOP (Firebase + Reactjs + Redux + MaterialUI)
- https://github.com/Kelvinfox1/SocialMediaSimulator (MERN Stack)
- https://github.com/Kelvinfox1/PawaTripRN2 (Android app)

Backend

- https://github.com/Kelvinfox1/circularity (Nodejs , GraphQl)
- https://github.com/Kelvinfox1/modugreens_api
- https://github.com/Kelvinfox1/KYC-Verification-for-Banks---Ethereum (Ethereum blockchain)

Figma Projects

- https://www.figma.com/file/ZxRIzQwqRMR1s10ByQBGAA/Pedni-Landing- Page? Node-id=0%3A1
- https://www.figma.com/file/ZxRIzQwqRMR1s10ByQBGAA/Pedni-Landing- Page
- https://www.figma.com/file/znPQnGYGyEtRF9jtFvelbU/email-verified- experience

Projects – Playstore

- QUICK GARAGE
- QUICK GARAGE MECHANIC SK-SYSTEMS
- MATATU LOAD MODUGREENS KUDISHI APP

Education

Software Engineering, Multimedia University, Nairobi September 2016 – December 2021

A fully integrated approach to the science and engineering of all that makes Software creation possible

This has provided me with the knowledge required to design, implement, operate and manage Software systems. I have gained technical and practical skills to help me develop into an engineering professional, ready to contribute to the economy, social and technological development of the business community

Relevant Courses: Software Project management, Distributed Systems Development, Information Systems Modelling, Specification of Software Systems, Software Evolution, Software Quality, Agile Methods

St Teresa's Boys High School January 2011 – November 2014

I completed my high school education and attained an average grade of B

Internships

Software Engineer at Viktech Solution, Kenya

- Created Database object like Tables, Table spaces, Rollback Segments, Multiplexing Control files, Data files, Implemented scripts to help rollout and managed Oracle in a global distributed environment
- Installed, configured and maintained oracle database on Linux and Solaris environment

Skills

- Software Development Test Automation Machine Learning Web Development
- API Development JavaScript Debugging Data Structures SQL Docker Products
- Design Adobe Photoshop User Experience Driving Database Management
- Innovator Oracle Enterprise Manager PHP programming Firebase NoSQL Heroku PAAS
- Restful API Arduino programing Python Angular JavaScript GIT Human centred design

Reference

Victor Mahasi from Viktech Solutions

Viktechsolutions.vs@gmail.com 0726491210

Eric Munene from Virdismart Global

cirenemunene@gmail.com 0722517627